<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629-xhtml.ent" [
<!-- One method to get references from the online citation libraries.
     There has to be one entity for each item to be referenced.
     An alternate method (rfc include) is described in the references. -->
<!ENTITY RFC5321 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5321.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC5322 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5322.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC5890 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5890.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC6532 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6532.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC7535 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7535.xml">
]>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" docName="draft-ietf-regext-epp-eai-01"
  category="std" ipr="trust200902" obsoletes="" updates=""
  submissionType="IETF" xml:lang="en" symRefs="true" sortRefs="false"
  tocInclude="true" version="3" consensus="true">
  <!-- xml2rfc v2v3 conversion 2.47.0 -->
  <front>
    <title abbrev="Use of EAI in EPP">Use of Internationalized Email Addresses in EPP protocol</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-regext-epp-eai-01"/>
    <author fullname="Dmitry Belyavskiy" initials="D." surname="Belyavskiy">
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>8 marta st.</street>
	  <city>Moscow</city>
	  <code>127083</code>
          <country>Russian Federation</country>
        </postal>
        <phone>+7 916 262 5593</phone>
        <email>beldmit@gmail.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author fullname="James Gould" surname="Gould">
      <organization>VeriSign, Inc.</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>12061 Bluemont Way</street>
          <city>Reston</city>
          <region>VA</region>
          <code>20190</code>
          <country>US</country>
        </postal>
        <email>jgould@verisign.com</email>
        <uri>http://www.verisigninc.com</uri>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date month="July" year="2021" day="25"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>
   This document describes an EPP extension that permits usage of Internationalized Email Addresses in the EPP protocol
   and specifies the terms when it can be used by EPP clients and servers.
	 The Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP), being developed before appearing the standards
	 for Internationalized Email Addresses (EAI), does not support such email addresses.
      </t>
      <t>TO BE REMOVED on turning to RFC: The document is edited in <eref target="https://github.com/beldmit/eppeai"> the dedicated github repo</eref>. Please send your submissions via GitHub.
      </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <t>
	<xref target="RFC6530" format="default"/> introduced the framework for Internationalized Email Addresses.
	To make such addresses more widely accepted, the changes to various protocols need to be introduced.
      </t>
      <t>
   This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) extension that permits usage of Internationalized Email Addresses in the EPP protocol
   and specifies the terms when it can be used by EPP clients and servers.  A new form of EPP extension, referred to as a Functional Extension, is defined and used
   to apply the rules for the handling of email address elements in all of the <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/> extensions negotiated in the EPP session,
   which include the object and command-responses extensions. The described mechanism can be applied to any object or command-response extension that uses an email address.
      </t>
      <t>
	The Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) specified in <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/>
	is a base document for object management operations and an extensible framework that maps
  protocol operations to objects. The specifics of various objects managed via EPP is described in separate documents.
  This document is only referring to an email address as a property of a managed object, such as
  the &lt;contact:email&gt; element in the <xref target="RFC5733" format="default">EPP contact mapping</xref> or
  the &lt;org:email&gt; element in the <xref target="RFC8543" format="default">EPP organization mapping</xref>, and command-response
  extensions applied to a managed object.
      </t>
        <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Conventions Used in This Document</name>
        <t> The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT", "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT",
  "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted
  as described in BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119" format="default"/> <xref target="RFC8174" format="default"/> when, and only when,
  they appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Migrating to Newer Versions of This Extension</name>
      <t>
   Servers that implement this extension <bcp14>SHOULD</bcp14> provide a way for
   clients to progressively update their implementations when a new
   version of the extension is deployed.  A newer version of the
   extension is expected to use an XML namespace with a higher version
   number than the prior versions.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="emailAddressSpec" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Email Address Specification</name>
      <t>
	      Support of non-ASCII email address syntax is defined in <xref target="RFC6530" format="default">RFC 6530</xref>. This mapping does not prescribe minimum or maximum lengths for character strings used to represent email addresses.
        The exact syntax of such addresses is described in Section 3.3 of <xref target="RFC6531" format="default"/>. The validation rules introduced in RFC 6531 are considered to be followed.
      </t>
      <t>
        The definition of email address in the EPP RFCs, including Section 2.6 of <xref target="RFC5733" format="default"/> and
        Section 4.1.2, 4.2.1, and 4.2.5 of <xref target="RFC8543" format="default"/>, references <xref target="RFC5322" format="default"/> for the email address syntax.  The XML schema
        definition in Section 4 of <xref target="RFC5733" format="default"/> and Section 5 of <xref target="RFC8543" format="default"/> defines the "email" element using the type "eppcom:minTokenType",
        which is defined in Section 4.2 of <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/> as an XML schema "token" type with minimal length of one.  The XML schema "token" type will fully support the use
        of EAI addresses, so the primary application of the EAI extension is to apply the use of <xref target="RFC6531" format="default"/> instead of <xref target="RFC5322" format="default"/> for
        the email address syntax.  Other EPP extensions may follow the formal syntax definition using the XML schema type "eppcom:minTokenType" and the <xref target="RFC5322" format="default"/> format specification,
        where this extension applies to all EPP extensions with the same or similar definitions.
      </t>
      <t>
        The email address format is formally defined in Section 3.4.1 of <xref target="RFC5322" format="default"/>, which only consists of printable US-ASCII characters for both the local-part and the domain ABNF rules.
        In <xref target="RFC6531" format="default"/>, the extends the Mailbox, Local-part and Domain ABNF rules in <xref target="RFC5321" format="default"/> to support "UTF8-non-ascii", defined in Section 3.1 of <xref target="RFC6532" format="default"/>, for the local-part and
        U-label, defined in Section 2.3.2.1 of <xref target="RFC5890" format="default"/>, for the domain.  By applying the syntax rules of <xref target="RFC5322" format="default"/>, the EPP extensions will
        change from supporting only ASCII characters to supporting Internationailzed characters both in the email address local-part and domain-part.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Functional Extension</name>
      <t>
        <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/> defines three types of extensions at the protocol, object, and command-response level, which impact the structure of the EPP messages.  A Functional Extension
        applies a functional capability to an existing set of EPP extensions and properties.  The scope of the applicable EPP extensions and applicable extension properties are defined in the Functional Extension along with the
        requirements for the servers and clients that support it.  The Functional Extension needs to cover the expected behavior of the supporting client or server when interacting with an unsupporting client or server.
        Negotiating support for a Functional Extension is handled using the EPP Greeting and EPP Login services.</t>
    </section>

    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Internationalized Email Addresses (EAI) Functional Extension</name>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
  	    <name>Scope of Functional Extension</name>
  	    <t>
           The functional extension applies to all object extensions and command-response extensions negotiated in the EPP session that include email address properties.
           Examples include the &lt;contact:email&gt; element in the <xref target="RFC5733" format="default">EPP contact mapping</xref> or
           the &lt;org:email&gt; element in the <xref target="RFC8543" format="default">EPP organization mapping</xref>.  All registry zones (e.g., top-level domains) authorized
           for the client in the EPP session apply.  There is no concept of a per-client, per-zone, per-extension, or per-field setting that is used to indicate
           support for EAI, but instead it's a global setting that applies to the EPP session.
  	    </t>
      </section>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
  	    <name>Signaling Client and Server Support</name>
  	    <t>
           The client and the server can signal support for the functional extension using a
           namespace URI in the login and greeting extension services respectively.  The
           namespace URI "urn:ietf:params:xml:ns:epp:eai-0.2" is used to signal support for the functional extension.
	   The client includes the namespace URI in an &lt;svcExtension&gt; &lt;extURI&gt; element of
           the <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/> &lt;login&gt; Command.  The server includes the namespace URI
           in an &lt;svcExtension&gt; &lt;extURI&gt; element of the <xref target="RFC5730" format="default"/> Greeting.
  	    </t>
      </section>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
  	    <name>Functional Extension Behavior</name>
          <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      	    <name>EAI Functional Extension Negotiated</name>
	    <t>
		    If both client and server have indicated the support of the EAI addresses during the session establishment,
		    it implies possibility to process the EAI address in any message having an email property during the established EPP session.
              	Below are the server and client obligations when the EAI extension has been successfuly negotiated in the EPP session.
      	    </t>
      	    <t>The server MUST satisfy the following obligations when the EAI extension has been negotiated:</t>
      	    <ul>
      	    <li>Accept EAI compatible addresses for all email properties in the EPP session negotiated object extensions and command-response extensions.
                For example the &lt;contact:email&gt; element in <xref target="RFC5733" format="default"/> and the &lt;org:email&gt; element in <xref target="RFC8543" format="default"/>.</li>

	    <li>Accept EAI compatible addresses for all registry zones (e.g., top-level domains) authorized for the client in the EPP session.</li>
	    <li>Email address validation based on EAI validation rules defined in <xref target="emailAddressSpec" format="default"/></li>
	    <li>Storage of email properties that supports internationalized characters.</li>
	    <li>Return EAI compatible addresses for all email properties in the EPP responses.</li>
          </ul>

          <t>The client MUST satisfy the following obligations when THE EAI extension has been negotiated:</t>
          <ul>
      	    <li>Provide EAI compatible addresses for all e-mail properties in the EPP session negotiated object extensions and command-response extensions.  For example the &lt;contact:email&gt; element in <xref target="RFC5733" format="default"/> and the &lt;org:email&gt; element in <xref target="RFC8543" format="default"/>.</li>

      	    <li>Provide EAI compatible addresses for all registry zones (e.g., top-level domains) authorized for the client in the EPP session.</li>

      	    <li>Accept EAI compatible addresses in the EPP responses for all email properties in the EPP session negotiated object extensions and command-response extensions.</li>
      	  </ul>
        </section>

        <section numbered="true" toc="default">
          <name>EAI Functional Extension Not Negotiated</name>
          <t>
            The lack of EAI support can cause data and functional issues, so an EAI supporting client or server needs to handle cases where the opposite party doesn't support EAI.
            Below are the server and client obligations when the EAI extension is not negotiated due to the lack of support by the peer.
          </t>
          <t>The EAI supporting server MUST satisfy the following obligations when the client does not support the EAI extension:</t>
            <ul>
              <li>When the email property is required in the EPP extension command, the server SHOULD validate the email property sent by the client using the ASCII email validation rules.</li>
              <li>When the email property is optional according the EPP extension command, if the client supplies the email property the server SHOULD validate the email property using the ASCII email validation rules.</li>
              <li>When the email property is required in the EPP extension response, the server MUST validate whether the email property is an EAI address and if so return the predefined placeholder email (see below) and otherwise return the email property that has been set.</li>
              <li>When the email property is optional in the EPP extension response, the server MUST validate whether the email property is an EAI address and if so don't return the email property in the response and otherwise return the email property that has been set based on server policy.</li>
            </ul>

            <t>The EAI supporting client MUST satisfy the following obligations when the server does not support the EAI extension:</t>
              <ul>
                <li>When the email property is required in the EPP extension command and the email property is an EAI address with no alternative ASCII address, the client MUST provide the predefined placeholder email address (see below).</li>
                <li>When the email property is optional in the EPP extension command and the email property is an EAI address with no alternative ASCII address, the client SHOULD omit the email property.</li>
              </ul>
        </section>
        <section numbered="true" toc="default">
		<name>EAI Placeholder Email Address</name>
		<t>
			A valid email value needs to be provided to a non-EAI supporting client or server to satisfy a required email property when all that is available is an EAI value.  To satisfy this requirement, a predefined placeholder email needs to be selected that meets the requirements:
		</t>
			<ul>
				<li>A syntactically valid email address to pass client or server validation logic.</li>
				<li>A non-EAI email address since the client or server doesn’t support EAI email addresses.</li>
				<li>A single value that can indicate the lack of EAI support to the client or server.</li>
				<li>An email address that is blackholed and never delivered.</li>
				<li>Use of the email address will not cause operational issues.</li>
			</ul>
		<t>
			<xref target="RFC7535" format="default">RFC 7535</xref> defines a blackholed domain name with EMPTY.AS112.ARPA, which can be leveraged for the EAI predefined placeholder email.  The proposal is to define the predefined placeholder email value as EAI@EMPTY.AS112.ARPA.
	</t>
        </section>

    </section>
    </section>

    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Security Considerations</name>
      <t>
	Registries <bcp14>SHOULD</bcp14> validate the domain names in the provided email addresses.
	This can be done by validating all code points according to IDNA2008 <xref target="RFC5892" format="default"/>.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>IANA Considerations</name>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>XML Namespace</name>
        <t> This document uses URNs to describe XML namespaces and XML schemas
   conforming to a registry mechanism described in  <xref target="RFC3688" format="default">RFC 3688</xref>.  The
   following URI assignment should be made by IANA:</t>
        <t> Registration request for the eai namespace:</t>
        <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
   URI:  urn:ietf:params:xml:ns:epp:eai-0.2
   Registrant Contact:  IESG
   XML:  None.  Namespace URIs do not represent an XML specification.

   Registration request for the eai XML Schema:

   URI:  urn:ietf:params:xml:schema:epp:eai-0.2
   Registrant Contact:  IESG
   XML:  See the "Formal Syntax" section of this document.
]]></artwork>
      </section>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>EPP Extension Registry</name>
        <t>
   The EPP extension described in this document should be registered by
   IANA in the "Extensions for the Extensible Provisioning Protocol
   (EPP)" registry described in RFC 7451 <xref target="RFC7451" format="default"/>.  The details of the
   registration are as follows:
        </t>
        <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
   Name of Extension: Use of Internationalized Email Addresses
                      in EPP protocol
   Document status:  Standards Track
   Reference:  TBA
   Registrant Name and Email Address:  IESG, <iesg@ietf.org>
   Top-Level Domains(TLDs):  Any
   IPR Disclosure:  None
   Status:  Active
   Notes:  None
]]></artwork>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Implementation Considerations</name>
      <t>
	Registries MAY apply extra limitation to the email address syntax (e.g. the addresses can be limited to Left-to-Right scripts). These limitations are out of scope of this document.
      </t>
    </section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references>
      <name>References</name>
      <references>
        <name>Normative References</name>
        <reference anchor="RFC2119" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc2119" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Key words for use in RFCs to Indicate Requirement Levels</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC2119"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="2119"/>
            <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
            <author initials="S." surname="Bradner" fullname="S. Bradner">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="1997" month="March"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>In many standards track documents several words are used to signify the requirements in the specification.  These words are often capitalized. This document defines these words as they should be interpreted in IETF documents.  This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC3688" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc3688" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3688.xml">
          <front>
            <title>The IETF XML Registry</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC3688"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="3688"/>
            <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="81"/>
            <author initials="M." surname="Mealling" fullname="M. Mealling">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2004" month="January"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document describes an IANA maintained registry for IETF standards which use Extensible Markup Language (XML) related items such as Namespaces, Document Type Declarations (DTDs), Schemas, and Resource Description Framework (RDF) Schemas.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        &RFC5321;
        &RFC5322;
        <reference anchor="RFC5730" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5730" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5730.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP)</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC5730"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5730"/>
            <seriesInfo name="STD" value="69"/>
            <author initials="S." surname="Hollenbeck" fullname="S. Hollenbeck">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2009" month="August"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document describes an application-layer client-server protocol for the provisioning and management of objects stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in XML, the protocol defines generic object management operations and an extensible framework that maps protocol operations to objects.  This document includes a protocol specification, an object mapping template, and an XML media type registration.  This document obsoletes RFC 4930.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC5733" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5733" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5733.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Contact Mapping</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC5733"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5733"/>
            <seriesInfo name="STD" value="69"/>
            <author initials="S." surname="Hollenbeck" fullname="S. Hollenbeck">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2009" month="August"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) mapping for the provisioning and management of individual or organizational social information identifiers (known as "contacts") stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in Extensible Markup Language (XML), the mapping defines EPP command syntax and semantics as applied to contacts.  This document obsoletes RFC 4933.   [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        &RFC5890;
        <reference anchor="RFC6530" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6530" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6530.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Overview and Framework for Internationalized Email</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC6530"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="6530"/>
            <author initials="J." surname="Klensin" fullname="J. Klensin">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <author initials="Y." surname="Ko" fullname="Y. Ko">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2012" month="February"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>Full use of electronic mail throughout the world requires that (subject to other constraints) people be able to use close variations on their own names (written correctly in their own languages and scripts) as mailbox names in email addresses.  This document introduces a series of specifications that define mechanisms and protocol extensions needed to fully support internationalized email addresses.  These changes include an SMTP extension and extension of email header syntax to accommodate UTF-8 data.  The document set also includes discussion of key assumptions and issues in deploying fully internationalized email.  This document is a replacement for RFC 4952; it reflects additional issues identified since that document was published.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
  </reference>
  <reference anchor="RFC6531" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6531">
<front>
<title>SMTP Extension for Internationalized Email</title>
<author initials="J." surname="Yao" fullname="J. Yao">
<organization/>
</author>
<author initials="W." surname="Mao" fullname="W. Mao">
<organization/>
</author>
<date year="2012" month="February"/>
<abstract>
<t>This document specifies an SMTP extension for transport and delivery of email messages with internationalized email addresses or header information. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
</abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name="RFC" value="6531"/>
<seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC6531"/>
</reference>
&RFC6532;
        <reference anchor="RFC7451" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc7451" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7451.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Extension Registry for the Extensible Provisioning Protocol</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC7451"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="7451"/>
            <author initials="S." surname="Hollenbeck" fullname="S. Hollenbeck">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2015" month="February"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>The Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) includes features to add functionality by extending the protocol.  It does not, however, describe how those extensions are managed.  This document describes a procedure for the registration and management of extensions to EPP, and it specifies a format for an IANA registry to record those extensions.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC8174" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8174" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Ambiguity of Uppercase vs Lowercase in RFC 2119 Key Words</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC8174"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="8174"/>
            <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
            <author initials="B." surname="Leiba" fullname="B. Leiba">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2017" month="May"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>RFC 2119 specifies common key words that may be used in protocol  specifications.  This document aims to reduce the ambiguity by clarifying that only UPPERCASE usage of the key words have the  defined special meanings.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
      </references>
      <references>
        <name>Informative References</name>
        <reference anchor="RFC5892" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5892" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5892.xml">
          <front>
            <title>The Unicode Code Points and Internationalized Domain Names for Applications (IDNA)</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC5892"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5892"/>
            <author initials="P." surname="Faltstrom" fullname="P. Faltstrom" role="editor">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2010" month="August"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document specifies rules for deciding whether a code point, considered in isolation or in context, is a candidate for inclusion in an Internationalized Domain Name (IDN).  </t>
              <t>It is part of the specification of Internationalizing Domain Names in Applications 2008 (IDNA2008).  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
	&RFC7535;
        <reference anchor="RFC8543" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8543" xml:base="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8543.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Organization Mapping</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.27487/RFC8543"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="8543"/>
            <author initials="L." surname="Zhou" fullname="L. Zhou">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <author initials="N." surname="Kong" fullname="N. Kong">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <author initials="J." surname="Yao" fullname="J. Yao">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <author initials="J." surname="Gould" fullname="J. Gould">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <author initials="G." surname="Zhou" fullname="G. Zhou">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2019" month="March"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) mapping for provisioning and management of organization objects stored in a shared central repository.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
      </references>
    </references>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Change History</name>
      <section anchor="change-00-to-01" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Change from 00 to 01</name>
        <ol spacing="normal" type="1">
          <li>Changed from update of RFC 5733 to use the "Placeholder Text and a New Email Element" EPP Extension approach.</li>
        </ol>
      </section>
      <section anchor="change-01-to-02" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Change from 01 to 02</name>
        <ol spacing="normal" type="1">
          <li>Fixed the XML schema and the XML examples based on validating them.</li>
          <li>Added James Gould as co-author.</li>
          <li>Updated the language to apply to any EPP object mapping and to use the EPP contact mapping as an example.</li>
          <li>Updated the structure of document to be consistent with the other Command-Response Extensions.</li>
          <li>Replaced the use of "eppEAI" in the XML namespace and the XML namespace prefix with "eai".</li>
          <li>Changed to use a pointed XML namespace with "0.2" instead of "1.0".</li>
        </ol>
      </section>
      <section anchor="change-02-to-03" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Change from 02 to 03</name>
	<ol spacing="normal" type="1">
	  <li>The approach has changed to use the concept of Functional EPP Extension.</li>
	  <li>The examples are removed</li>
        </ol>
      </section>
      <section anchor="change-03-to-04" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Change from 03 to 04</name>
	<ol spacing="normal" type="1">
	  <li>More detailed reference to email syntax is provided</li>
	  <li>The shortened eai namespace reference is removed</li>
        </ol>
      </section>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
